<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<info:toolkitInfoModel xmlns:common="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/common"
 xmlns:info="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/toolkitInfo">
 <info:identity>
   <info:name>com.ibm.streamsx.kafka</info:name>
   <info:description>
The Kafka toolkit integrates IBM Streams with Apache Kafka brokers. It can be used with following broker versions:

* 0.10.2
* 0.11
* 1.0
* 1.1
* 2.0

# Additional information

+ What's new and what has changed

This is an overview of changes for major and minor version upgrades. For details see the Releases in public Github.

++ What's new in version 1.7.1

* operator metrics which got invalid for an operator are flagged with a value of -1, for example the metric for the partition related consumer lag after de-assignment of a partition from a consumer operator
* when not in a consistent region, offsets are committed when partitions are rebalanced within a consumer group. After re-assignment, messages are fetched beginning with the previously committed offsets. The periodic commit controlled by the **commitCount** parameter is reset after rebalance.
 
++ What's new in version 1.7.0

* The default value for the **commitCount** parameter has changed from 500 to 2000.
* SPL types for standard messages have been added to the toolkit

++ What's new in version 1.6.0

* The KafkaProducer exposes many performance metrics of the producer client as operator metrics
* The most important producer configs have default values, which result in higher reliability and throughput. These are `retries`, `compression.type`, `linger.ms`, `batch.size`, and `max.in.flight.requests.per.connection`.
* New operator parameter **guaranteeOrdering** for the KafkaProducer, which guarantees that the sequence in a topic partition is the same as the order of tuples in case of retries.
* Queue control for the KafkaProducer operator to stabilize the maximum queue time and to avoid timeouts sending records
* The KafkaConsumer operator exposes some performance metrics of the consumer client as operator metrics, like the lag for each topic partition.

   </info:description>
   <info:version>1.7.1</info:version>
   <info:requiredProductVersion>4.2.0.0</info:requiredProductVersion>
 </info:identity>
 <info:dependencies/>
</info:toolkitInfoModel>
