<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (C) 2010,2012-2014, International Business Machines Corporation -->
<!-- All Rights Reserved                                                   -->
<info:toolkitInfoModel xmlns:common="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/common" xmlns:info="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/toolkitInfo">
  <info:identity>
    <info:name>com.ibm.streamsx.kafka</info:name>
    <info:description>
The Kafka toolkit project is an open source IBM InfoSphere Streams toolkit project.
It is focused on the development of operators and functions that help you use InfoSphere Streams
to interact with Kafka messaging systems. 

The operators provide the ability for InfoSphere Streams applications to send and receive data
from a queue or topic that is posted on Kafka server.


The `KafkaProducer` and `KafkaConsumer` operators support Kafka v0.10.0.0 brokers. For 0.9 brokers, you make rebuild the toolkit for Kafka 0.9 by running the following commands:
`ant clean; ant kafka-0.9` For older versions of Kafka brokers, you must use older versions of this toolkit.  

For example:
* The `CreateProducer` API creates a message producer to send messages to the specified destination.
* The `CreateConsumer` API creates a message consumer for the specified destination.
* The `CreateConnection` API creates a connection that uses a specified user identity. The specified user identifier and password are used to authenticate the application.


+ Developing and running applications that use the Kafka Toolkit

To create applications that use the Kafka Toolkit, you must configure either Streams Studio
or the SPL compiler to be aware of the location of the toolkit. 

# Before you begin

* Install IBM InfoSphere Streams.  Configure the product environment variables by entering the following command: 
      source product-installation-root-directory/4.0.0.0/bin/streamsprofile.sh
  
  The toolkit ships with a set of required clients, and therefore this configuration
  is not needed.
  

# About this task

After the location of the toolkit is communicated to the compiler, the SPL artifacts that are specified in the toolkit
can be used by an application. The application can include a use directive to bring the necessary namespaces into scope.
Alternatively, you can fully qualify the operators that are provided by toolkit with their namespaces as prefixes.

# Procedure

1. Review the list of restrictions for the InfoSphere Streams specialized toolkits in the product documentation.

2. Verify that the appropriate environment variables are set for the Kafka messaging systems that you use.

3. Configure the SPL compiler to find the toolkit root directory. Use one of the following methods:
  * Set the **STREAMS_SPLPATH** environment variable to the root directory of a toolkit or multiple toolkits (with : as a separator).
    For example:
        export STREAMS_SPLPATH=$STREAMS_INSTALL/toolkits/com.ibm.streamsx.kafka
  * Specify the **-t** or **--spl-path** command parameter when you run the **sc** command. For example:
        sc -t $STREAMS_INSTALL/toolkits/com.ibm.streamsx.kafka -M MyMain
    where MyMain is the name of the SPL main composite.
    **Note**: These command parameters override the **STREAMS_SPLPATH** environment variable.
  * Add the toolkit location in InfoSphere Streams Studio.
4. Develop your application. To avoid the need to fully qualify the operators, add a use directive in your application. 
  * For example, you can add the following clause in your SPL source file:
        use com.ibm.streamsx.kafka::*;
    You can also specify a use clause for individual operators by replacing the asterisk (\*) with the operator name. For example: 
        use com.ibm.streamsx.kafka::KafkaConsumer;
5. Build your application.  You can use the **sc** command or Streams Studio.  
6. Start the InfoSphere Streams instance. 
7. Run the application. You can submit the application as a job by using the **streamtool submitjob** command or by using Streams Studio. 
</info:description>
    <info:version>1.0.0</info:version>
    <info:requiredProductVersion>4.2.0.0</info:requiredProductVersion>
  </info:identity>
  <info:dependencies/>
  <info:resources>
    <info:messageSet name="MessagingResource">
      <info:lang default="true">en_US/MessagingResource.xlf</info:lang>
    </info:messageSet>
  </info:resources>
</info:toolkitInfoModel>
